

MANU MOHAN HSE OFFICER



CONTACT



Phone

+97430317823



Email

manumonan9288@gmaii.com



Address

Mohanam (H)
Paruthur (Po)
Pallippuram, Pal



PERSONAL INFO

NATIONALITY : INDIAN

FATHER : MADAN MOHAN

DATE OF BIRTH : 30/09/1988 MARITAL STUTUS : MARRIED PASSPORT NO : H 1147551



EDUCATION

SSLC

2003-2004

Board of Public Examination,

PLUS TWO
2005-2006
Board of Higher Secondary
Examination ,Kerala



PROFILE

Well-qualified HSE Officer with over 8 years of experience. Provide the necessary leadership to contribute towards an effective safety organization & formulating safety policies to suggest improvement needed for job execution. The main objective being able to create a safe, Healthy and environmentally acceptable working conditions throughout the projects



WORK EXPERIENCE

SALES EXECUTIVE-

2021 - Present

SMART TECHNO SOLUTIONS-Security Systems & Automation Muthuthala, Pattambi

HSE OFFICER -

2018 - 2019

ACI STEEL CO.WLL

(ALBA POTLINE 6 PROJECT)

Bahrain

() HSE OFFICER -

2016 - 2018

BSS TRADING AND CONTRACTING CO.WLL (DAM HOUSING PROJECT)

Bahrain

HSE OFFICER -

2011 - 2015

M/S ANTELEC LTD

Mumbai

(Bajaj Auto Ltd at Pune (India)

Tech Mahindra Ltd at Pune (India)

Daimler Chrysler India Ltd at Pune(India))



TECHNICAL QUALIFICATIONS

Diploma in Fire & Safety Engineering - 2009

National institution of fire & safety Engineering - Thrissur,

Kerala

Diploma Industrial & Construction safety Engineering National institution of fire & safety Engineering - Thrissur, Kerala

Fire Fighting Training -2009

National institution of fire & safety Engineering - Thrissur, Kerala

- NEBOSH IGC Level -3 -2017
 UK Certificate
- IOSH Managing Safety 2017
 UK Certificate
- OSHA -30
 US Department of Labor



LICENSE NO : 880956020 LICENSE TYPE :-

- i. Private Saloon
- ii. Private less than 16 Passenger
- iii. Private Conveyance
- iv. private Goods Vehicle Pick-up



LANGUAGE

- English
- Malayalam
- Hindi



HOBBEIS

- Reading
- Cricket
- Farming



MY REFERENCE

- Implementation of safety policies and Safety procedures.
- > To develop awareness among employees about the necessity of the safety programmed in their routine activities, also encourage them to take safety as a habit or part of life more than mandatory.
- > To develop the company's documentations like HSE plan, Road safety plan, Waste management plan, Emergency plan etc...per training to the client requirements.
- Prepare Daily/Weekly/ safety reports returns for submission to client.
- Prepare Accidents / Incidents to find out the causes and adopting proper preventive measure.
- > To investigate all accidents & near missies for rout case & Recommendation to prevent similarities, prepare reports follow up on recommendation.
- Prepare activity Risk assessment to all jobs, before the start of any job with the project team.
- Ensure to conduct various trainings including Emergency procedures, Construction safety Training, Office training, Drivers Training etc...
- Ensure to provide HSE orientation for the new employees in co-ordination with safety Department.
- Ensure conducting Tool Box Meeting for workers and supervisors.
- > Ensure the use of Personal Protective Equipment (PPE) by the all employees at the required area and situations.
- Ensure all work permit conditions are fully adhered.
- Responsible for all HSE educational programs.
- Make employees to think of various Hazardous / Unsafe conditions involved in various operations before they are starting the work and hence to avoid unnecessary loss of man-hours & property.
- Carry out inspection on construction site and advice on various HSE issues to Construction team.
- Inspect equipment, machineries and Tools to ensure its safest and proper use to avoid and bypassing of safety devices.
- Maintained Material Safety Data Sheet (MSDS)on chemicals used in the work place.
- ldentified, recommended and implemented ergonomic changes to reduce health and safety hazards.
- > Ensuring the quality of the Personal Protective Equipment and workmen acceptance to use them.
- Performed daily walk through for safety inspections of the facilities including fire systems. Documented and photographed findings and complied and presented statistical data on safety actives to EH&S director. Co-ordination of fire extinguisher where necessary.

DECLARATION

I do hereby declare that all the details given above are true to the best of my knowledge and belief and I will put my best effort to keep the company's goal of I am selected.

MANU MOHAN .A